抱歉
Sorry.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不习惯进自己的房间敲门
I'm not used to knocking on my own door.
没事
That's okay.
刚才是不是有小孩子的声音
Did I hear a child's voice?
他爸爸刚送他过来
His dad just dropped him by.
我周末照顾他
I get him on weekends.
莫纳克打扰到你了吗
Is Monarch bothering you?
没有  他...没事
No. He's -- he's -- he's fine.
你认识莱斯利对吗
So, you know, uh, Lezley?
没人不认识莱斯利
Everybody knows Lezley...
不论他们承认与否
Whether they want to admit it or not.
你现在住在那里吗
You staying over there now?
不是  我
No. I...
我只有那天晚上在那儿  然后...
I just went over there the other night and...
一直没走
Never left.
我年轻的时候经常去那里
I used to go there a lot when I was younger.
就像成年礼一样
It's like a rite of passage.
原来之前是那样的
So that's what that was.
你可以喝完啤酒  丹尼尔
You can finish your beer, Daniel.
你想待到什么时候都行
Take as long as you like.
你走的时候门会自己锁上
The door, it'll lock behind you.
我还是拿着啤酒走吧
I'll just take it with me.
这个...
It's...
丹尼尔
Daniel.
什么事
Yes?
小心点
Be careful.
你是特别中意我
Was it me,
还是说昨晚陪你的人换谁都可以
or could it have been anybody last night?
有时候...
Sometimes...
我做事没有什么理由
I do things I don't have a good answer for.
我懂
I understand.
食品超市
丹尼尔·霍顿
Daniel Holden.
如风般自由
As free as the wind blows.
感觉很真实  对吧
Feels real, don't it?
食品超市
做好准备吧
Fixing to warm up.
对赖账的人有好处
It's good for catfish.
我不需要知道怀孕几周了  小泰
I don't think I need to know how many weeks it was, Teddy.
爸爸只会是你一个人
I was there with you.
我知道  我...
Oh, I-I know. I just --
我只是觉得往一根小棒棒上尿尿
I just thought it was interesting
就能什么都知道
you could pee on a stick now,
这很有意思  仅此而已
and they'd tell you all that. That's all.
可能将来都能判断
I mean, one day it'll be able to tell you
是男还是女了呢
if it's a boy or girl, you know?
我可不想马上全知道
I don't think I want to know all that at once.
都三分钟了
It's been three minutes.
我不敢看
I can't look.
天哪
Oh, my God.
-什么  -你怀孕了
- What? - You're pregnant.
真的吗
Really?
上面显示已经五周多了
Says more than five weeks.
天哪
Oh, my God!
-我现在可以说吗  -说什么
- Can I say this right now? - What?
你这个烤炉里正烤着小面包呢
You got a bun in the oven right there.
不  不能这么说
No. You can't say that.
好吧  那这么说呢
All right. How about this?
就说  说"我们怀孕了"
How about -- how about "We're pregnant"?
不行
No.
那...
How about...
"你怀孕了"  托妮·塔尔博特
"You're pregnant," Tawney Talbot?
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
是的吧
I guess I am.
*千真万确  不可否认*
*Ain't no lie, can't deny*
*千真万确*
*Ain't no lie*
不可否认
Can't deny.
我为此祈祷过
I prayed about this.
真的吗
You did?
我只是祈祷遵循上帝的旨意
I just prayed that God's will be done, you know?
我就只知道这么做  遵循上帝的旨意
And that's all I knew to do -- his will be done.
然后你就怀孕了
And you're pregnant.
天哪  你怀孕了
By God, you're pregnant.
是啊  小泰
I am, Teddy.
我怀了你的孩子
With your baby.
小泰
Teddy?
什么事  托妮
Yeah, Tawney?
我才刚怀孕不久
It's still early.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我们能先保密吗
Can we keep it a secret?
就我们两个人先高兴一会儿
Enjoy it for a little while, just you and me?
你肯定不会相信
You ain't gonna believe it.
又一棵倒了
Another one fell.
又一棵
Another one?
不同的树
Different tree.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我忘记时间了
I lost track of time.
三天了  丹尼尔
Three days, Daniel.
我不是给你留言了吗
I thought I left you a message.
那是周四早上留的
That was Thursday morning.
对
Right.
我和泰德昨晚开车到处找你
Ted and I had to drive around last night looking for you.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我差点就报警了
I-I almost called the sheriff.
我真的不想报警
I really didn't want to do that.
我知道你不是小孩子  丹尼尔  但是
I know you're not a teenager, Daniel, but...
但是你也不是那么...
But you're also not --
正常
Normal.
你的人生一直都不太正常
Your life hasn't been normal,
你又能指望什么呢
so how could you expect to be?
我只是想知道你的下落
Like, I just want to know where you are.
好吗  亲爱的
All right, sweetheart?
好
Of course.
我先走了
I-I have to go.
我得去准备
I have to get ready.
准备什么
For what?
我要去参加盖恩斯先生的葬礼
I thought I would go to Mr. Gaines' funeral.
你...
That's...
考虑得真周到
thoughtful.
我回来后帮你干活
I'll do some work when I get back.
你之后会回家  待上一段时间吗
So, you're coming home, then, and staying for a while?
是这么打算的
I plan to, yes.
我想借...借点钱买东西
I need to borrow some -- some money for some things.
多少
How much?
50块就够了
$50 will be okay.
我找到工作后就还给你
I'll pay you back when I get a job.
这个我不担心
I'm not worried.
一旦我开始工作
And once I start working,
我可能还要买辆二手车开...
I-I-I might even buy an old beater truck or...
你肯定会赚到钱买车的
I could see you in one of those.
好
Yeah.
你  你怎么过去
How -- how are you gonna get there?
我想走路过去
I thought I'd walk.
开车去吧
Take the car.
我不想一直开你的车  母亲
I don't want to keep taking your car, mother.
我不想让你走路过去  丹尼尔
I don't want you to walk, Daniel.
开吧
Please.
注意安全
Be careful.
卢瑟福生前是我的挚友
Rutherford was a good friend.
他思想敏锐
Had a sharp mind.
特别会打桥牌
He played a spirited game of bridge.
不过高尔夫打得不怎样
Wasn't much on the golf course.
他打高尔夫就像是出于义务或者去忏悔的
He just kind of did that out of obligation or penance.
我知道他是位伟大的父亲
I know that he was a great father.
我们会想念他
We'll miss him.
我的天哪
Holy mother of God.
我不知道自己上来说几句话
I-I'm not sure if it's appropriate for...
是不是合适
for me to say something or not.
当然  我这样确实讽刺
The irony of it doesn't escape me, of course.
总而言之
Anyway, uh...
盖恩斯先生在我离开的那段时间里经常送书给我
Mr. Gaines used to send me books when I was away.
单单是法国大革命的书就给我送了三本
Three books on the French revolution alone.
他应该喜欢革命  尤其是失败的革命
He liked revolutions, I guess, especially failed ones.
我发现那些书都贯穿着同一个主题
I discovered a theme running through those books --
那就是  人会看到想看的
That men will see what they want to see
相信想相信的
and believe what they want to believe
并且为自己的信念浴血奋战
and fight to the death for those beliefs,
不论多么误入歧途  多么无望
no matter how misguided or hopeless.
我经常做梦梦到革命
Oftentimes I would dream on these events,
梦到人群占领街道广场
of the crowds taking the streets, taking the squares,
恐惧在人群中蔓延
and the contagion of menacing fear,
仁慈为人们所不齿
and mercy be damned.
偶尔我会...
And occasionally, I would...
我会看到盖恩斯先生  置身人群之外
I would see Mr. Gaines, away from the crowd.
和他目光相汇
Catch his eye and...
你会明白在这群疯狂陶醉的人面前
understand just how difficult it is
两个人的目光要汇集到一起
for two people to come together
是一件多么艰难的事
in the face of such intoxicating lunacy.
事实上  我不认识盖恩斯先生
Truth is, I didn't know Mr. Gaines.
算不上认识
Not really.
他随书附写的便条从来不涉及个人私事
His notes that accompanied the books were never personal.
只是谈谈身边发生的事儿
They just talked of the subject matter at hand.
起初我不在意他是否附加那些便条
At first I didn't care if he sent them or not.
我...
I...
但是我都看了
But I read them.
他一直寄
And he kept sending them
寄了19年
for 19 years.
就像我说的
Like I said, I...
我不知道我为什么来这儿
I don't know why I'm here exactly.
我想理由可能是
I suppose it might reason that...
我为他穿上这身葬礼服是因为
...I dressed up for him because on more than one occasion...
他不止一次为我这么做过
...he dressed up for me.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
他到底在搞什么
What the hell was that about?
无耻  厚颜无耻
Gall. Pure gall.
那你觉得他能接受这份认罪协议了吗
So, you think this plea deal is gonna happen?
我认为她希望如此
I think she wants it to happen.
她就能摆脱困扰了
Get it out of her hair.
从一开始我就不应该支持那个贱人
I never should have backed that bitch in the first place.
你觉得他会接受认罪协议吗
You think he'll take it?
霍顿吗
Holden? Shit.
谁知道他会怎么做
Who knows what he'll do?
他能容忍别人尿他身上呢
He let a man piss on him.
乔治·梅尔顿到底去哪儿了  卡尔
Where is George goddamn Melton, Carl?
你确定要找他吗
Are you sure you want to find him?
但你仍然把霍顿视为威胁
But you still see Holden as a threat.
对谁的威胁
To who?
对社会
The community.
我不愿意和他做邻居
I wouldn't want to live next to him.
你愿意吗
Would you?
你有什么事瞒着我吗  卡尔
You keeping secrets from me, Carl?
野花和咖啡
Wildflowers and coffee.
老天
Jesus.
我不得不承认  霍顿可真有创意
Holden's creative. I'll give him that.
问题是小泰不愿意起诉
Problem is, Ted Jr. won't press charges.
那我们必须给这小子讲讲道理
Well, then we just got to talk some sense into that boy.
你手上都有两起勒晕和性侵的案子了
You got two choke-outs and two sexual assaults.
你认为这是一个巧合吗
You think that's a coincidence?
所以我才我提起这件事
That's why I brought it up.
这是作案手法  卡尔
It's modus operandi, Carl.
这真是天赐良机
It's a gift from the gods.
它能把认罪协议这种无稽之谈扼杀在摇篮里
It'll nip this plea-deal nonsense in the bud.
我从法律角度跟小泰谈过了
I discussed the legal side with Ted Jr.
他说他不想这件事令他尴尬
Said he doesn't want the embarrassment of it.
而且对此情绪非常激烈
Felt pretty strong about it, too.
我对他的小情绪无能为力
I can't help his little feelings.
霍顿把咖啡豆塞进他屁眼时事情就无法改变了
The die was cast when Holden shoved coffee beans up his ass.
议员先生  要续杯吗
Hey. Refill, Senator?
怎么不叫我"亲爱的"了
What happened to calling me "Sweetie"?
亲爱的  续杯吗
Refill, sweetie?
真听话
Attagirl.
是咖啡渣  罗兰
It was grounds, Roland.
-什么  -不是咖啡豆  是咖啡渣
- What? - Not beans. Grounds.
小泰说他并没有真塞
And Teddy said there wasn't actual penetration.
我才不管有没有真塞
I don't give a good God damn.
你跟我说没有一个检察官
You tell me any backwoods prosecutor
能说服陪审团相信他是蓄意的
couldn't convince a jury that that was the intent.
他肯定不会真的都给他硬塞进去啊
He damn sure wasn't making sand castles back there.
我们得找小泰做笔录
We just got to get Junior on the record.
他不会乐意的
He ain't gonna like this.
肯定不会
Not one bit.
这件事比他重要  卡尔
Well, this is bigger than him, Carl.
这件事比我们所有人都重要
This is bigger than all of us.
你告诉我这件事是对的
You did the right thing telling me this.
现在别给我怂了
Don't go soft on me now.
8美元的饭付60美元吗
$60 on an $8 meal?
今晚去你那儿方便吗
You up for a little visit later?
今晚我儿子在  议员先生
Got my son tonight, Senator.
你搅得一位老人家心神不宁了
You're messing with an old man's heart.
所以你才会继续回来找我啊
That's why you keep coming back for more.
别笑了
Stop laughing.
保持一步一步往前走就好
Just keep one foot in front of the other.
乔恩
Jon.
-没事了  -你又一次死里逃生
- Okay. - You've escaped death once again.
这是家族遗传
It's in the family DNA.
霍顿家族不可战胜  是吧
Holdens are invincible, huh?
都是超级英雄
Superheroes.
先生们  贴近你身边的女士
Men, bring your ladies close.
情侣舞时间到了
It's time for a couples dance.
我喜欢你  乔恩·斯特恩
I like you, Jon Stern.
我们应该确定关系吗
Should we go steady?
你为什么不闭嘴直接吻我
Why don't you shut up and kiss me?
当着所有人面吗
In front of all of Paulie?
我不在乎谁看着我们
I don't care who sees us anymore.
我不敢相信你就要走了
I can't believe you're about to leave.
就几天而已
For a few days.
死囚牢在向你招手
Death row beckons?
我会回来的
I'll be back.
然后你会再离开
And then you'll leave again.
我们不必非得如此吧
Doesn't have to be this way.
能至少给我一份分别礼物吗
Do I at least get a parting gift?
抱歉打扰了
Excuse me.
首先你哥哥在盖恩斯先生的葬礼上出现
First your brother shows up at Mr. Gaines' funeral
不知道胡言乱语什么
rambling about God knows what,
现在你们在这儿的行为就像...
and now here you are acting like...
我明白你必须过自己的生活
I know you have to live your life.
我理解这点
I understand that.
我明白你的处境不是你的错
I know it's not your fault, the position you're in.
但是你们能去别处这样做吗  拜托
But could you go do it somewhere else, please?
这样我们就能不去想汉娜
So that we don't have to think about Hanna
以及那晚她的遭遇
and what happened to her that night?
那时你多大
How old were you then?
5岁
5?
-乔恩  不要  -不  说真的
- Jon, please. - No. Really.
8岁
8?
我那时年纪够大了
I was old enough.
足够大干什么
Old enough. For what?
听你的父母告诉你那些事
To listen to what your parents told you
因为他们说的是真的而深信不疑吗
and believe it because they said it was true?
害怕自己动脑子想想吗
Afraid to think for yourself.
害怕看到所有事实真相吗
Scared to look at all the facts.
为什么这样
And for what?
这样你才永远不必承认
So you'd never have to admit to yourself
你自己也许是错的
that you might be wrong.
你能去别处这样做吗
Could you go do that somewhere else?
拜托了
Please.
晚安
Good night.
祝你好运
And good luck.
丹尼尔在盖恩斯的葬礼上胡言乱语了吗
Daniel was rambling at Gaines' funeral?
我不知道
I don't know.
而我们在溜冰场上纵情欢愉
And here we are, living it up at the skating rink.
对世事漠不关心
Not a care in the damn world.
我们早就该注意的
We should have known better.
我早该注意的
I should have known better.
没关系的  乔恩
It's okay, Jon.
我是说  去她的  管她撞见什么呢
I mean, screw her and the minivan she came in.
我们要担心的不是她
It's not her we should be worried about.
你说得对
That's right.
差点忘了
Almost forgot for a second.
蓝药丸  白药丸
Blue pill, white pill.
丹尼尔
Daniel?
我叫查理
My name's Charlie.
是你找我吗
Did you call for me?
我没找你
I didn't call for you.
我是牧师
I'm the chaplain.
赞美上帝
Praise God.
什么
What?
如果你想说话  我就在这儿
I'm here if you want to talk.
我不想说话
I don't want to talk.
那你介意我就坐在这儿吗
You mind if I just sit here, then?
你做什么随便你
I don't care what you do.
牧师查理
Charlie the chaplain.
Charlie chaplain.
你反射弧够长的
Took you long enough.
我头脑不像以前那么敏锐了
I'm not as sharp as I used to be.
这样对你来说会更好些吗
Does that work better for you
不像以前那么敏锐会更好些吗
not being as sharp as you used to be?
闭嘴  查理牧师
Shut up, Charlie chaplain.
我没什么别的意思
I'm not making a point.
只是问问
Just asking.
我更希望你待在默片时代
I liked you better in the silent era.
这个厨房早就该装修了
This kitchen is long overdue for a remodel.
我知道妈妈很兴奋
I know mom's psyched.
你真是个敏感的人  杰瑞德
You're a sensitive person, Jared.
这是个很好的特点
It's a good trait.
妈妈说警方
Mom said that the Sheriff's department
退回了一些我的个人物品
returned some of my possessions from the, um...
我的随身听和一些其它东西
my walkman and other things.
其他东西我都找到了  就是没找到随身听
I found the other items, but I-I didn't find my walkman.
我想我会找到它的
I'm sure it'll turn up.
那是名里有个Z的莱斯利
Well, that'll be Lezley with a "Z."
我该走了
Better go.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
怎么了  杰瑞德
Yes, Jared?
你知道今天是什么日子吧
D -- you know what today is, right?
我们亲爱的母亲的生日
The day of our dear mother's birth.
派对两点开始
2:00 is the party.
我会到的
I'll be there.
汉娜当时还只是个孩子
Hanna was just a baby back then.
但我当时并没有那么想她
I didn't think of her that way at the time...
也许因为我也只是个孩子吧
I guess 'cause we were all just babies.
有好奇心是好事  杰瑞德
It's good to be curious about things, Jared...
尤其是对禁忌之事
Especially when those things are somehow taboo.
只是要
You just got to be...
小心
careful.
钱给我
Give me the money.
你就拿着微波炉和摩尔炖肉
Now, you get the microwave and the dinty moore
事情我来谈
and let me do the talking.
塔特  我是莱斯利
Tater, it's Lezley.
谁
Who?
莱斯利
Lezley!
稍等
Hold on a minute!
我得找找裤子
I got to find my pants.
快穿吧
I second that motion.
叫你把裤子穿上
Put your pants on!
你带了我要的酒  吉普赛人
You brought my liquor, gypsy man.
正宗的尊尼获加  塔特
Johnnie Walker no less, Tater.
好吧  还有什么
All right. What else?
一台几乎全新的微波炉
A slightly used microwave oven.
一盒摩尔炖肉
A case of dinty moore.
还有五十美元
And $50 cash.
-我要100块  -60块
- $100 cash. - $60.
75块
$75.
70块成吗
$70?
好吧  成交
Okay. Deal.
谢谢
Thank you.
你欠我20美元
You owe me $20.
你看什么看
What are you looking at?
去把手推车拿来
Go get the dolly.
这玩意儿不轻
This son of a bitch is gonna be heavy.
我不想要他的东西
I-I don't want to take this man's stuff.
你觉得愧疚啦
You feeling guilty?
你总是这样吗
It's kind of a constant refrain with you, ain't it?
恐怕你得重视一下
You might ought to look into that.
这炉子自从八年前塔特妻子去世
Look, this stove ain't been used since Tater's wife
他就没用过了
died eight years ago.
这炉子对他不过是回忆而已
Stove ain't nothing more than a memory to him now, really.
记忆还是应该放在脑子里
Might as well keep it up in his head where memories belong.
给厨房添置个微波炉说不定还能有点用
Have a microwave in the kitchen he can actually use.
我不知道
I don't know.
不知道什么
You don't know what?
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know what to do.
那是因为你总是犹犹豫豫  丹尼尔
That's 'cause you're stuck, Daniel.
这样你居然还能活着
Surprised you ain't dead.
你总是胡扯  莱斯利
You're full of shit, Lezley.
至少我接受自己这样
At least I'm okay with it.
你能接受你自己吗
You okay with what you are?
你现在要么去取手推车
Now either go get the dolly
或者去把那瓶威士忌从塔特那抢回来
or pry that bottle of scotch from Tater's mitts.
你选哪个我都无所谓
I don't give a shit either way.
妈  让我来抹蛋糕吧
Mom, please let me frost the cake.
-我可以的  -我知道
- I can do it. - I know you can,
但已经让你自己烤你的生日蛋糕了
But you've already baked your own birthday cake.
怎么还能让你抹蛋糕呢  对吧  爸爸
You shouldn't have to frost it. Right, dad?
今天是妈妈的生日
It's mom's birthday.
我们应该按她的想法来
I guess she can do what she wants.
我去车库把椅子取出来吧
Want me to get the chairs out of the garage?
谢谢  泰德
Thank you, Ted.
你和爸怎么了
What's going on with you and dad?
你得先抹层底衣
You need to do a crumb coat first.
好吧
Okay.
我不懂
I don't know what that is.
还不如我来呢
It's just easier if I do it.
不行  妈妈
No, no. Mom.
教我一下吧
Tell me.
先抹上薄薄的一层让它固定住
You put a light layer on first and then let it sit.
好的  没问题
Okay. Cool.
到了
Here we go.
是呀
Yep.
你是说了"是呀"吗
Did you just say "Yep"?
是呀
Yep.
啰嗦一句  这是我妈妈第一次
To state the obvious, this is mom's first birthday ever
和所有孩子一起过生日
with all of her children.
我要当着你
And I'm going to make a promise
和这些气球的面发誓
in front of you and all these balloons
我保证对大家和和气气的
that I'm going to be nice to everyone.
包括泰德吗
Including Ted Jr.?
但愿如此吧
Pray for me.
妈妈在厨房吗
Mom in the kitchen?
还能在哪
Where else?
能帮个忙吗
Would you?
-我来吧  -谢谢
- I'm on it. - Thank you.
生日快乐  妈妈
Happy birthday, mom.
谢谢  宝贝
Oh, thank you, sweetheart.
你有没有带...
Did you bring the --
带了
I did.
放最上面吗
Should I put it up top?
火腿也在里面呢
Oh, the ham is in there.
好吧
Got it.
我都懒得问你
I'm not even gonna ask
是怎么说服妈妈让你来抹她的生日蛋糕的
how you got her to let you frost her own birthday cake.
少见啊
A first.
看起来如何
Does it look okay?
看起来...
It looks like, um...
一看就知道你第一次干这活
you've never done it before.
我谢谢你  老姐
Thanks a lot, sister.
东西带了吗
Did you get the stuff?
东西都让乔恩拿到那个屋了
Jon's got everything in the other room.
好的  我要走了
Okay. I'm gonna go.
好  走吧
Yeah. Go.
-好的  -我这就走
- Okay. - I'm going. I'm going.
丹尼尔在吗
Is Daniel here?
杰瑞德说他和朋友出去了
Uh, Jared said he went off with a friend.
挺好的
That's good.
但他知道有派对
But he knows.
他会回来的
He'll be back.
当然了  妈妈
Of course, mom.
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
你们好
Hey, y'all. Hey.
你好  托妮
Hey, Tawney.
你好  小泰
Hey, Teddy.
你好  阿曼莎
Hi, Amantha.
托妮  谢谢你  好漂亮
Tawney, thank you. They're lovely.
很高兴你喜欢  小泰
Oh, I'm glad you like them. Teddy.
单独聊聊行吗
Got a minute?
当然
Yeah. Sure.
这边
Here.
我得浇汁了
Oh, I need to finish the glaze.
不行
Nope.
今天是你生日  妈妈
It's your birthday, mom.
今天不许你工作
You are officially off duty.
但是豆子
But the beans --
托妮
Tawney.
豆子我来弄就行了  珍妮特
I-I'll do the beans, Janet.
妈妈  你只要去坐好
Mother, you are just gonna have to sit down
喝杯红酒
and have a glass of wine
享受一大家子的温馨陪伴就行了
and enjoy the delightful company of your charming family.
-我得先摆桌子  -有我们呢  妈
- I should set the table. - We got it, mom.
喝吧  享享福
Drink. Be merry.
要帮忙吗  哥们儿
Need a boost there, buddy?
我够的到
I can reach it.
看看你高高在上的样子  杰瑞德
Look at you getting all tall on us, Jared.
你们不必如此麻烦的
Y'all didn't have to go to all this fuss.
不麻烦
No fuss.
只是想着今年要比以往隆重一点
Just thought we'd do a little extra this year, considering.
生日快乐  妈妈
Happy birthday, mom.
谢谢  小泰
Thank you, Teddy.
要是你没进来
It'd be a lot better
看他们布置这些就更好了
if you weren't in here seeing them do this.
-你好  小泰  -你没事吧
- Hi, Teddy. - You all right?
我怎么了
Why?
不知道
I don't know.
你到现在还没讽刺过我
You ain't said nothing smart aleck to me yet.
别高兴的太早
Don't push your luck.
喝点吗
Thirsty?
好啊
Sure.
真高兴你俩终于公开了
Good to see you guys finally came out of the closet.
一切顺利[希伯来语]
Mazel tov.
说这话合适吗
Is that appropriate?
谢谢  小泰
Thank you, Teddy.
托妮  "一切顺利"很合适
And, yes, Tawney, "Mazel tov" is appropriate.
好极了  哥们儿
Good deal, brother.
你们要去哪旅游
Where you gonna travel to?
也去了温哥华
Also went to vancouver.
你怎么想  妈妈
What do you think, mom?
不如我们先吃吧
Maybe we should go ahead and eat?
都快一个小时了
It's been almost an hour.
等他回来了再加个盘子嘛
We can make a plate for him for when he gets here.
再等等行吗
Maybe wait a little bit longer?
可以
Okay.
有机的
Organic.
你要开始买这种东西了吗
Is that what you're gonna start buying now?
有机的东西
Organic stuff?
天呐  太好吃了
Oh, my goodness. That was good, good, good.
-谢谢  -堪称饕餮大餐
- Thank you. - Everything was wonderful.
-美味  -真是大饱口福
- Delicious. - Everything was wonderful.
-我都吃撑了  -谢谢
- I can't eat another bite. - Thank you.
我饱了
I'm stuffed.
土豆做得很棒
Potatoes are awesome.
-谢谢  -吃得停不下来
- Thanks. - Can't stop eating them.
我相信大家一致同意
I think everyone can agree that father time
我的漂亮妻子一天比一天年轻
is working in reverse on my beautiful wife.
别这样说
Oh, now.
祝你生日快乐  宝贝
Happy birthday, sweetheart.
谢谢  泰德
Thank you, Ted.
祝你生日快乐  妈妈
Happy birthday, mom.
妈妈  我还想告诉你
Mom, I also just want to say how much
你对我和托妮来说意义重大
you mean to me and Tawney,
我希望你知道  任何事...
And, and I just hope that you know that anything...
请进
Come on in.
生日快乐  妈妈
Happy birthday, mother.
对不起我来晚了
I'm so sorry I'm late.
-我...  -没事
- I... - It's okay.
我们刚要吃蛋糕
You're just in time for cake.
这是谁  丹尼尔
Who's your friend, Daniel?
这位是...
This is, um
莱斯利  名里是个"z"
Lezley. With a "Z."
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - How do you do?
他帮我挑了送你的礼物
He was helping me, um, find your present.
找得可不容易了
One of my more difficult rummages.
谢谢你费心
Well, thank you for your efforts.
没有白费力气
Oh, it was well worth the challenge,
因为这场合如此特别
considering the circumstances of this special occasion.
我们把礼物拿进来吧
Shall we go get her?
好的
Yes.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
好的  妈妈
Okay, mother.
进来吧
Come on through.
这是个韦奇伍德炉  我们谈过的
It's a wedgewood, like we talked about.
对  就跟你给我看的照片上的一样
R-right, like the, the photo you showed me,
韦奇伍德炉
a-a wedgewood.
我以为这是你想要的
I-I thought it was what you wanted.
现在用不着啊
Well, I-I thought maybe down the line,
但这很贴心  丹尼尔
but it's lovely, Daniel.
好使吗
Does it work?
卖家跟我保证最后一次用的时候没问题
I was assured when it was last used, there was no issue.
可能需要抛光一下
Some refinishing might be appropriate.
但得连上燃气管道
But you got to run a gas line in.
房子里有燃气管道吗
Got a gas main line in the house?
没有  我们家都用电
No. It -- it's all electric.
那样可不便宜
That won't be cheap.
也不是不可能  小泰
It can be done, Teddy.
当然了
Oh, yeah. Sure. I mean, you know.
你只需要把上面的电炉砸烂
Of course, you just got to rip up the electric stove top there,
把烤箱从墙里拽出来
pull the ovens out of the wall, you know, that sort of thing.
但是  一切皆有可能
But...anything's possible.
这是个不错的礼物  丹尼尔
It's a nice gift, Daniel.
想得很周到
Very thoughtful.
当然了
It sure is.
但我们不必非得现在开始用
But w-we don't need to decide right now.
我们可以先放在车库里以后再用
We can put it in the garage for later.
换做我  我就现在开始安
If it was me, I'd do it right now,
正好有人给你演示
While you're in the middle of a demo.
真的不用拆很多东西
I mean, it's not much to take this out, really.
你还有空间安燃气管道
And you have room to run the gas line in here.
这上面  橱子里
Up here, cabinets.
这下面  抽屉里  等等
Down here, drawers, what have you.
然后把韦奇伍德炉放那儿
Wedgewood right there.
我一直很喜欢煤气炉
I always liked gas stoves.
从小家里就有个
Had one growing up.
我觉得用它做饭会更好吃点
I think they make things taste just a little better.
当然还得有你妈妈这样的厨艺
If that's possible with your mother's cooking.
这只是我的想法
I'm just saying if it was me.
现在
Right now...
我们先去吃蛋糕吧
Let's have some cake.
过来吃吧  丹尼尔
Come on, Daniel.
对不起我骂你是...
I'm sorry I said that you were...
混蛋
Full of shit.
对
Yes.
你要收回这句话吗
You taking it back?
不
No.
我相信是命运带你来我的店里
I believe forces brought you out to my establishment
找炉子送你妈妈当生日礼物
in search of a stove for your mama's birthday.
只要用心聆听  命运也会指引你前方的路
Same forces will tell you where to go next if you listen.
有时候很难听到声音
Sometimes it's hard to hear.
没错
Yeah.
我们痛苦时  总能听得更清楚
Well, we usually hear better when we're in pain.
但该死  万一你经受不住痛苦呢
But, damn, if you ain't got a high threshold.
后会有期  伙计
See you around the fringes, buddy.
我现在该去哪儿  莱斯利
So, where to now, Lezley?
就在你的身后
Might ought to go look behind you.
家让我害怕
I'm afraid to.
是的
Yeah.
换做我也是
I would be, too.
这是个用完即抛的社会
I mean, it's a throwaway society.
没错
That's true.
我们买了东西  然后再丢掉
I mean, we buy stuff, and then we throw it away.
还不如借呢
I mean, why not lease it
使完后再还回去呢
and then give it back when we're done, you know?
让他们把东西送去垃圾场处理
Let them haul it off to the landfill.
说得好
Good point.
没错
Damn right.
你好  托妮
Hello, Tawney.
你好  丹尼尔
Hello, Daniel.
你看起来很平静
You look restful.
我感觉很平静
I feel restful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你呢
How are you?
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我...
Well, I'm...
我心中百感交集
I'm feeling a lot of things,
但肯定不平静
but, uh, I wouldn't say restful is one of them.
托妮  谢谢你
Well...Thank you, Tawney, for, uh...
那天帮了我
reach out for me on that day.
我希望我做得对  丹尼尔
I hope I did the right thing, Daniel.
我觉得你做得对
I think you did.
你触动我心扉  托妮
You made me feel, Tawney.
真真切切  你懂吗
Really feel, you know?
懂
Yes.
我很久没被触动了
For the first time in a long time.
这才是人之本性  不是吗
That's a big part of what makes us human, isn't it?
是的
I think so.
我觉得这会
I think it...
让内心变得丰满
deepens us.
我觉得内心丰满了不少
I've been deepened.
我们过会儿就得走了
We're gonna have to scoot here in a minute.
我问问托妮
See what Tawn--
各位
Hey, everybody.
我要宣布一个消息
I,h, got an announcement to make.
宝贝  你能过来下吗
H-hey, uh, baby, would you come here?
来  宝贝
Come here, baby.
妈妈  我们还有个礼物要送你
Mom, we got one more present for you.
她怀孕了
We're pregnant.
什么  天呐
What?! Oh, my gosh!
-惊喜吧  -托妮
- Surprise! - Tawney!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
-这是个好消息  儿子  -谢谢  爸爸
- That's good news, son. - Aw, thanks, dad.
我为你们俩高兴
I'm happy for you both.
太棒了
Oh, that's just wonderful.
我知道我本该保密
I know I wasn't supposed to say anything, you know,
但我迫不及待了
but I just -- I just couldn't wait.
就是等不及了
Just couldn't wait.
天呐
Oh, boy.
这里面有个小家伙了
There's a bun in that oven, buddy.
恭喜  泰德
Congratulations, Teddy.
-谢了  乔恩  -恭喜
- Thanks, Jon. - Congratulations.
乔恩和我也要宣布一件事
Jon and I have an announcement, too.
星期二  我去了梅肯的一家临终关怀医院
On Tuesday, I go to this hospice in Macon.
你是个圣人
You're a saint, Charlie.
那里有人去世
They're just people dying.
每天都会发生
Happens every day.
我要死了
Am I dying?
你想死吗  丹尼尔
Do you want to die, Daniel?
我妹妹总插手我的事
My sister keeps interfering.
你说清楚点
You're mumbling.
她长大了  爱管闲事
She's a little busybody, all grown up.
不管怎样
Anyway...
我为他们放音乐
I play music for them.
有时候我也只能放放音乐了
Sometimes that's all I do.
言语和音乐相比黯然失色
Words can pale in comparison.
你说得话肯定比不上
Yours sure do.
对一些人来说
Well, for some...
音乐是唯一能让他们安然入眠的东西
It's the only thing that will let them sleep.
给予他们慰藉
It's the only thing that gives them solace.
你有多久没听音乐了  丹尼尔
How long has it been since you've heard music, Daniel?
美终将救赎世界
Beauty will redeem the world.
你是个傻瓜  查理
You're a fool, Charlie.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
Daniel?